Ryan Chase

Full Stack Developer Portland, Oregon

503-367-7057 | ryan@chasery.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL. With over 10 years of experience in both UX Design and Development roles, I bring a user focused perspective to your team.

Skills

Design: Story Maps, User Flows, Rapid Prototyping, Usability Testing

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Emotion, Styled Components, JavaScript, React, NextJS

Back End: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, Test Driven Development, Deployment

Projects

Racking Up | Website: Created a full stack app to manage clothing purchases.

- Created client and server applications with test coverage.
- Deployed server and client to Heroku and Vercel.
- Stack: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Mocha, Chai, Jest

Noteful | GitHub: Developed an application for creating and categorizing notes.

- Used context to manage app wide state.
- Created API fetch requests to delete and post notes.
- Stack: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS

Experience

CAREMORE HEALTH | Cerritos, California

Sr. User Experience Designer

August 2017 - Present

- Led user experience for provider medical iOS app.
- Inspired systemic change in provider workflow, measured by an 85% reduction in documentation hours, by highlighting double documentation inefficiencies.
- Reduced dev team's time-to-market on new features by half, by creating a reusable component library.
- Mentored integrated UX team members through consistent feedback and support.

SUREID | Hillsboro, Oregon

User Experience Designer

April 2015 – May 2017

- Advised engineering teams on user experience best practices.
- Created applicant review app, reducing time to review by 50%, by employing usability best practices.
- Conducted and standardized usability testing on app features to drive user focused decision making.

DEALER SPIKE | Lake Oswego, Oregon

Lead Front-End Developer

December 2010 - April 2015

- Drove creation of responsive components and views, giving the SaaS company a market advantage to grow it's dealership customer base by 970%.
- Mentored a team of five front-end developers creating a reduction in development time of customer sites from one week to two days.

Education

THINKFUL May 2021

Full Stack Engineering

- Full stack software engineering with focus on JavaScript Web Development.
- Practical mastery of JavaScript, React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Deployment, Testing, and Version Control.